# ALVIN **JACKSON**

EXPERIENCED UX DESIGNER, DEVELOPER, AND RESEARCHER

Creating harmony between a product, a user, and a business is very essential. I am a strategist that tailors a well documented plan to build a solution for all team members, users, and stake holders. With the challenging ever changing requirements of people, products, and industries I thrive in creating a canvas of solutions.





p: 737-206-0715 e: hello@alvinjackson.com w: www.alvinjackson.com

# **SKILLS & TECH**



# **UX DESIGN**

8+ years creating adaptable experiences Invison, Adobe Suites, Basalmiq, Axure, Sketch and more



# **HTML & CSS**

3+ years building responsive UI for desktop and mobile using Visual Studio, Github, Bootstrap, and more.



#### **TEAM LEAD**

Working with teams and building products on time using Trello, Jira, Zoom, Skype and more.



## **USER RESEARCH**

Creating harmony through users and applications with current technologies such as Userzoom, Xmind, Validately



## **DEVELOP & LAUNCH**

Coordinating with dev. team, Finalize Designs, Speed Test, Micro Details, A/B Testing, and Launch



## EXPERIENCE

#### 10+ YEARS OF CREATING AND LEADING

## **INVENTIVE WORKS, LLC**

Senior Experience Designer | 2019 - present

Assist in the creative direction of the user experience and design flow regarding applications interface. My work is a compilation of ux design and user research strategies. Using Trello ensures strong team communication, as we take concepts to produced design mockups, prototypes, and development to meet aggressive deadlines.

## **VESTOR POCKET, LLC**

Senior Experience Designer and Project Lead | 2017 - present
Recent Projects | SA Shoe & Company, Livestock Loader, LLC, DebonaireU

As project lead, there is a development cycle I use. Beginning with research and preplanning I am able to construct a strong data analysis, user stories, and user flow. Exploration and design then take place using IA, wireframes, style guide and mockups. The prototype and design elements are then pushed to the developers where communication is key. Once the product is developed quality testing and launch is accomplished. In some projects, the entire process is not necessary and I am able to modify, update or redesign where needed.

#### FIRST UNITED CORP.

Senior UX and PM | 2017 - 2018

First United Corp. is a real estate investment firm that was seeking an online image to bridge the gap between them and potential clients. Through an extensive marketing campaign, I created the user experience and design of websites and multiple landing pages to help bring profitable leads for all investors within the firm. I designed, implemented content, analyzed competitors web pages and websites for continuous improvement while achieving top Google rankings and generating profitable leads.

#### **MEDIAFUSION DIGITAL MEDIA PLATFORM**

Lead UX and UI | 2016 - 2017

Mediafusion is a service that allows churches, events and other businesses to share while living their content on mobile, desktop and tv devices. As lead designer I created the user experience and interface of a Netflix style application that could easily be added to their customer's website. This project contract also entailed me creating all marketing and branded materials. Skills and technologies used: HTML, CSS, Basalmiq, Wireframe, Invisionapp prototyping, javascript, Jira, Adobe Suites.

## **ALVARA GROUP, LLC**

Lead / Senior UX | 2011-2016

As Senior Experience Designer with Alvara Group, I lead many projects consisting of enterprise projects like Hearst Media that needed a product that maximized profits and production. The daily work consisted of team collaboration, interviews, research and design. Skills used: Jira, Basalmiq, Wireframe, Invisionapp prototyping, HTML, CSS, Content Management Systems, user research and data, Adobe Suites.

#### **EDUCATION**

Inventive Academy, LLC - Full Stack Engineering, 2019
Nielsen Norman Group - UX Conference, 2018
Devry University - BA 2006

